Guide to the Stanford Family Library Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers
  - "Thoughts on Religion, and Other Subjects. By Blaise Pascal. A New Translation, and a Memoir of His Life, by the Rev. Edward Craig, A. M. Oxon. Member of the Wernerian Society. To Which are Added Introductory and Other Notices. First American Edition." by Blaise Pascal. Amherst, MA: J. S. and C. Adams, 1829 (Box 17)
  - "The Rule and Exercises of Holy Dying: In Which Are Described the Means and Instruments of Preparing Ourselves and Others Respectively for a Blessed Death; and the Remedies Against Evils and Temptations Proper to the State of Sickness; Together with Prayers and Acts of Virtue to Be Used by Sick and Dying Persons or by Others Standing in Their Attendance. And Rules for the Visitation of the Sick, and Offices Proper for That Ministry. To Which is Added, the Golden Grove. First American, from the twenty-seventh London edition." by Jer. Taylor (edited by Thomas Thirlwall). Philadelphia: W. W. Woodward, 1811 (Box 17)
  - "The Beautiful City in Song, and Other Poems" by Dwight Williams. New York: Phillips & Hunt, 1887 (Box 17)
  - "Orator's Own Book; compiled by the editor of Waldie's Library" Philadelphia: Crissy, Waldie & Co., 1835 (Box 18)
  - "Tracts" New York: The Protestant Episcopal Tract Society, undated (Box 18)
  - "Philosophy of Eating" by Albert J. Bellows. New York: Hurd and Houghton, 1868 (Box 18)
  - "Fair Maid of Connaught and Other Tales for Catholic Youth" by Kate Duval Hughes. New York: P. J. Kennedy, 1889 (Box 18)
  - "Life Beyond" by George H. Hepworth. New York: E. P. Dutton & Company, 1896 (Box 18)
  - "Imitation of Christ" by Thomas A. Kempis. New York: E. P. Dutton & Company, 1891 (Box 18)
  - "Wells of Baca, Or, Solaces of the Christian Mourner.. .; from the 30th London edition." by J. R. Macduff. New York: Robert Carter and Brothers, 1879 (Box 18)
  - "Wells of Baca, Or, Solaces of the Christian Mourner.. .; 34th edition." by J. R. Macduff. London: James Nisbet & Co., undated (Box 18)
  - "Little Mother" by M. L. Shepard. Boston: James H. Earle, 1887 (Box 18)
  - "Sermons" by T. De Witt Talmage. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1872 (Box 18)
  - "Holy Bible" New York: American Bible Society, 1860 (Box 19)
  - "Address delivered before the young men's state association of the state of New York at their first annual meeting, at Geneva, September 2, 1841" by Amos Dean. Albany: J. Munsell (Box 19)
  - "Pinnock's improved edition of Dr. Goldsmith's History of Greece" by Oliver Goldsmith. Philadelphia: Thomas, Cowperthwait & Co., 1847 (Box 19)
  - "Crown our heroes and other poems: by Mary E. Kail. Washington, D.C.: Judd & Detweiler, 1887 (Box 19)
  - "Solitude sweetened, or, Miscellaneous meditations, on various religious subjects" by James Meikle. Hartford: S. Andrus and Son, 1844 (Box 19)
  - "System of Logic, Ratiocinative and Inductive" by John Stuart Mill. New York: Harper & Brothers, Publishers, 1864 (Box 19)
  - "Stepping Heavenward" by E. Prentiss. New York: Anson D. F. Randolph & Company, 1880 (Box 19)
  - "John Eax, and Mamelon; or, The South without the shadow" by Albion W. Tourgie. New York: Fords, Howard, & Hulbert, 1882 (Box 19)
  - "At the Beautiful Gate and other religious poems" New York: Anson D. F. Randolph & Company, 1883 (Box 20)
  - "Holy Bible" New York: E. Duyckinck, Smith and Forman, Collins and Co. J. Tiebout, S. A. Burtus, and B. Crane, 1812 (Box 20)
  - "Holy Bible" Cambridge, printed by C. J. Clay, M.A. & Son for the New York Bible and Common Prayer Book Society, undated (Box 20)
  - "Memorial of Ambrose Spencer" Albany: Joel Munsell, 1849 (Box 20)
  - "Mormon Country. A Summer with the Latter-Day Saints" by John Codman. New York ,: United States Publishing Company, 1874 (Box 20)
  - "Noontide at Sychar" by J. R. Macduff. London: James Nisbet & Co., undated (Box 20)
  - "Stepping Heavenward" by E. Prentiss. New York: Anson D. F. Randolph & Company, 1869 (Box 20)
  - "Divine Word Opened" by Jonathan Bayley. London: James Speirs, 1887 (Box 21)
  - "Moral Philosophy including Theoretical and Practical Ethics" by Jospeh Haven. Boston: Gould and Lincoln; New York: Sheldon and Company, 1873 (Box 21)
  - "Elements of Geometry and Trigonometry" by A. M. Legendre. New York and Chicago, A. S. Barnes & Company, 1872 (Box 21)
  - "New Treatise on Surveying and Navigation" by Oren Root. New York: Ivison, Phinney, Blakeman & Co.; Chicago: S. C. Griggs & Co., 1864 (Box 21)
  - "Fourteen weeks in natural philosophy" by J. Dorman Steele. New York and Chicago: A. S. Barnes & Co., 1872 (Box 21)
  - "Scholar's Guide to the History of the Bible" by T. Strong. Greenfield, Clark & Tylex, Denio & Phelps, Printers., 1822 (Box 21)
  - "Word-analysis: a graded class-book of English derivative words" by William Swinton. New York and Chicago: Ivison, Blakeman, Taylor and Company, 1874 (Box 21)
  - "People's money" by W. L. Trenholm. New York, Charles Scribner's Sons, 1893 (Box 21)
  - "Holy Bible containing the Old & New Testaments" Brattleborough, VT: printed for Holbrook & Fessenden, 1824 (Box 22)
  - "New Bryant and Stratton's Common School Book Keeping" New York: Smith & McDougal, Electrotypers, undated (Box 23)
  - "Vine and Olive; or Young America in Spain and Portugal" by William T. Adams. Boston :Lee and Shepard, 1876 (Box 23)
  - "Black's Guide to Killarney and the South of Ireland" by Adam and Charles Black. Edinburgh: Adam and Charles Black, 1879 (Box 23)
  - "A typical American; or, Incidents in the Life of Dr. John Swinburne of Albany" by The Citizen's Association. Albany, NY: Issued from the Citizen office, 1885 (Box 23)
  - "Lost in the Jungle" by Paul Du Chaillu. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1874 (Box 23)
  - "Rudiments of written Arithmetic" by Daniel W. Fish. New York and Chicago: Ivison, Blakeman, Taylor & Co., 1877 (Box 23)
  - "The destiny of man viewed in the light of his origin" by John Fiske. Boston: Houghton, Mifflin and Company; New York: The Riverside Press, 1887 (Box 23)
  - "Chinese and English phrase book, with the Chinese pronunciation indicated in English" by Benoni Lanctot. San Francicso: A. Roman & Company, 1867 (Box 23)
  - "The harp of Zion, a collection of poems, &c." by John Lyon. Liverpool: S. W. Richards, 1853 (Box 23)
  - "Key to the science of theology" by Parley P. Pratt. Liverpool: S. W. Richards, 1863 (Box 23)
  - "Catholocity, Protestantism and Infidelity" by F. X. Weninger. New York & Cincinnati: Benziger brothers printers to the Holy Apostolic See, 1871 (Box 23)
  - "Book of Mormon: an account written by the hand of Mormon upon plates taken from the plates of Nephi." Translated by Joseph Smith. Liverpool: Brigham Young, 1866 (Box 24)
  - "Great shipwrecks: a record of perils and disasters at sea -1544 to 1877" London: Thomas Nelson and Sons, Paternoster Row, undated (Box 24)
  - "Moral education: its laws and methods" by Joseph Rodes Buchanan. New York, printed for the author by S. W. Green's son, circa 1882 (Box 24)
  - "History of the conflict between religion and science; The International Scientific Series Vol XII" by John William Draper. New York: D. Appleton and Company, 1875 (Box 24)
  - "Rousseau" by John Morley. New York: Scribner and Welford, 1878 (Box 24)
  - "Elements of political economy" by Arthur Latham Perry. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1873 (Box 24)
  - "Tips and toe-weights; a natural and plain method of horse-shoeing" by Joseph Cairn Simpson. San Francisco, 1883 (Box 24)
  - "Wonder stories told for children" by Hans Christian Anderson. New York: Hurd & Houghton, 1872 (Box 25)
  - "Cast Up by the Sea" by Samuel W. Baker. Philadelphia: J. B. Lippincott & Co, 1875 (Box 25)
  - "Rifle and the Houndin Ceylon" by Samuel W. Baker. Philadelphia: J. B. Lippincott & Co, 1875 (Box 25)
  - "Burgh's dignity of human nature, to which is added, the proper method of preserving health" by Lewis Cornaro. Philadelphia: Thomas Stokes, 1851 (Box 25)
  - "Old-Fashoned Boy" by Martha Farquharson. Philadelphia: Stephen T. Souder, 1878 (Box 25)
  - "In the eastern seas, or the regions of the bird of paradise" by W. H. G. Kingston. London: T. Nelson and sons, 1876 (Box 25)
  - "New Elementary Algebra" by Horatio N. Robinson. New York: Ivison, Blakeman, Taylor & Co., 1872 (Box 25)
  - "My apingi kingdom: with life in the great sahara and sketches of the chase of the ostrich, hyena, etc." by Paul Du Chaillu. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1876 (Box 26)
  - "Stories of the gorilla country" by Paul Du Chaillu. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1875 (Box 26)
  - "The country of the dwarfs" by Paul Du Chaillu. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1876 (Box 26)
  - "Evidences of Christianity. Lectures before the Lowell Institute January, 1844." by Mark Hopkins. Boston: T. R. Marvin & son, 1886 (Box 26)
  - "Prayers for the use of families; or the domestic minister's assistant" by William Jay. New York: M. W. Dodd, 1853 (Box 26)
  - "Catskill Fairies" by Virginia W. Johnson. London: C. Kegan Paul & Co., 1881 (Box 26)
  - "Golden Robin, for the use of juvenile classes, public schools & seminaries" by W. O. Perkins. Boston: Oliver Ditson company; New York: C. H. Ditson & Co., undated (Box 26)
  - "The log of an ancient mariner being the life and adventures of Captain Edgar Wakeman" by Edgar Wakeman. San Francisco: A. L. Bancroft, 1878 (Box 26)
  - "A Contrast between Christianity and Calvinism by a Western Clergyman" Fredonia, NY: H. C. Frisbee, 1824 (Box 27)
  - "General Register of the Society of Colonial Wars 1899-1902" New York: Author of the General Assembly (Box 27)
  - "Pacific Coast First Reader; revised edition" San Francisco: A. L. Bancroft & Company, 1874 (Box 27)
  - "A Course of the French Language" by Louis Fasquelle. New York: Ivison, Blakeman, Taylor & Co., 1870 (Box 27)
  - "Fourth Reader" by William Torrey Harris, Andrew J. Rickoff and Mark Bailey. New York, Boston, and Chicago: D. Appleton and Company, 1880 (Box 27)
  - "Lineage Book, National Society of the Daughters ofthe American Revolution" by Susan Riviere Hetzel. Washington,DC: Harrisburg Publishing Company, 1902 (Box 27)
  - "My first voyage to southern seas: a book for boys" by William Henry Giles Kingston. London: T. Nelson and sons, Paternoster Row, 1874 (Box 27)
  - "Christian Remebrancer, or Short Reflections upon the Faith, Life, and Conduct of a Real Christian" by Jonathan Youmans. New York: Sleight and Robinson, 1830 (Box 27)
  - "For Family Worship, Part I - Scripture Readings, Part II - Family Prayers" by Lyman Abott. New York: Dodd, Mead & Company, 1883 (Box 28)
  - "The beauties of the British poets, with a few introductory observations" by George Croly. New York: C. Wells, 1831 (Box 28)
  - "Magnolia" edited by Henry W. Herpert. New York: A. & C. B. Edwards, 1841 (Box 28)
  - "The railroad as an element in education" by Alexander Hogg. Louisville, printed for the author., 1887 (Box 28)
  - "Christianity vindicated in seven discourses on the external evidences of the New Testament" by John Henry Hopkins. Burlington: Edward Smith, 1833 (Box 28)
  - "Education in its relation to manual industry" by Arthur MacArthur. New York: D. Appleton and Company, 1884 (Box 28)
  - ""Mitchell's primary geography, an easy introduction to the study of geography, designed for the instruction of children in schools and families." by S. Augustus Mitchell. Philadelphia: Thomas, Cowperthwait, 1853 (Box 28)
  - "The Gates Ajar" by Elizabeth Stuart Phelps. Boston: Houghton, Mifflin and Co., The Riverside Press, Cambridge, 1884 (Box 28)
  - "An I.D.B. in South Africa" by Louise Vescelius Sheldon. New York: John W. Lovell Company, 1888 (Box 28)
  - "Aids to Devotion, in three parts including Watt's guide to prayer" Boston: Licoln and Edmands, etc, 1831 (Box 29)
  - "Principles of Christian Philosophy" by John Burns. Philadelphia: Carey, Lea and Blanchard, 1833 (Box 29)
  - "Twenty-ninth Annual Report of the Superintendent of Public Schools for the School Year Ending June 30th, 1882" by Dept. of Public Schools, City and County of San Francisco. San Francisco: Barry, Baird & Co., Book and Job Printers (Box 29)
  - "Greatest Thing in the World" by Henry Drummond. New York: James Pott & Co., 1891 (Box 29)
  - "Eternal Hope: five sermons preached in Westminster Abbey, November and December, 1877" by Frederic William Farrar. New York: E. P. Dutton & Company, 1885 (Box 29)
  - "One Angel More in Heaven" by Saint Francis de Sales. New York, Cincinnati, and Chicago: Benziger Brothers, 1885 (Box 29)
  - "How to see Jesus with Fulness of Joy and Peace" by James William Kimball. Boston: James William Kimball, 1880 (Box 29)
  - "Supremacy of Law" by John P. Newman. New York: Hunt & Eaton; Cincinnati: Cranston & Stowe, 1890 (Box 29)
  - "Gates Ajar" by Elizabeth Stuart Phelps. Boston: Fields, Osgood, & Co., 1869 (Box 29)
  - "Voice Culture and Elocution" by William T. Rose. San Francisco: Payot, Upham & Co., 1886 (Box 29)
  - "Constitutional Guide; comprising the constitution of the United States" New York: G. C. Carvill & Co., Halstead & Voorhies etc., 1834 (Box 30)
  - "Nouveau Dictionnaire Anglais-Francais, et Francais-Anglais" Paris: Baudry, Librairie Europeenne, 1875 (Box 30)
  - "Farm Ballads" by William Carleton. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1873 (Box 30)
  - "Hearts and homes; or Social distinction" by Mrs. [Sarah Stickney] Ellis. New York: D. Appleton and Company, 1866 (Box 30)
  - "A Thousand and One Gems of Poetry" by Charles Mackay. London, George Routledge & Sons, undated (Box 30)
  - "Dick Sands, the Boy Captain" by Jules Verne. London: Sampson Low, Marston, Searle, & Rivington, 1881 (Box 30)
  - "The young detective, or, Which won?" by Rosa Abbott. Boston: Lee and Shepard, 1871 (Box 31)
  - "After death-what? or hell and salvation considered in the light of science and philosophy" by W. H. Platt. San Francisco: A. Roman & Co., 1878 (Box 31)
  - "Young man's book of knowledge" by Thomas Tegg. New York: J. P. Peaslee, 1834 (Box 31)